<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Zora Zorkić</title>
    <link>https://hzorkic.github.io/portfolio/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Zora Zorkić</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hzorkic.github.io/portfolio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>End-to-end Development of Texas Inventionworks&#39; Service Application</title>
      <link>https://hzorkic.github.io/portfolio/2023-11-22-texas-inventionworks-digital-infrastructure/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hzorkic.github.io/portfolio/2023-11-22-texas-inventionworks-digital-infrastructure/</guid>
      <description>Please Note: Some details of this project have been censored to honor confidentiality!
  📌 Project Scope  Client: Texas Inventionworks Timeline: Full-time, 3 months My Role: Lead-UX Researcher, Lead-UX Designer, Lead-UX Engineer Team: 2-3 student student staff members Methods: User Personas, User Flows, Wireframes, Rapid Prototyping Tools: Figma, Agile Scrum, AWS, React   🧠 Background During the summer of 2020, I co-led the development of a website to automate and digitize the operational workflow of Texas Inventionworks (TIW) (The University of Texas at Austin&amp;rsquo;s engineering school&amp;rsquo;s Makerspace).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Employee Experience Research for a Rapidly Scaling Organization</title>
      <link>https://hzorkic.github.io/portfolio/2024-02-04-employee-experience-research-for-a-rapidly-scaling-organization/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hzorkic.github.io/portfolio/2024-02-04-employee-experience-research-for-a-rapidly-scaling-organization/</guid>
      <description>Background In the ever-evolving landscape of innovation, Texas Inventionworks (TIW) stands as the epitome of a pioneering force in engineering and education at The University of Texas at Austin. As a dynamic &amp;ldquo;skunk works&amp;rdquo; initiative, TIW redefines the conventional engineering education paradigm. From its modest roots in a 1,700-square-foot lab, TIW has burgeoned into a multifaceted program. The expansion into the EER marked a pivotal moment, propelling TIW into exponential growth across technology, community outreach, and an expanding workforce.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
